Finding Aid for the James B. Coover Collection of Jazz Recordings, circa 1950-1957
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Prestige: PRLP 160, 1955?, 1 10-inch sound recording; analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural;; Album title: The Modern Jazz Quartet Performer(s): Jazz quartet: Milt Jackson, vibes; John Lewis, piano; Percy Heath, bass; Kenny Clarke, drums (Box 1, Item 55)
  Contents: All the things you are / Kern -- La Ronde; Vendome / Lewis -- Rose of the Rio Grande / Warren -- The queen's fancy; Delaunay's dilemma / Lewis -- Autumn in New York / Duke -- But not for me / Gershwin
- Prestige: PRLP 189, 1954, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, monaural; Monk, Thelonious Album title: Thelonious Monk Plays / Thelonious Monk Performer(s): Thelonious Monk, piano; others: Percy Heath; Art Blakey (Box 1, Item 56)
  Contents: Work -- Nutty -- Blue Monk -- Just a gigolo
- Riverside: 1003, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Ma Rainey, first of the great blues singers volume 1 Performer(s): Tampa Red, guitar; The Tub Jug Washboard Band (Box 1, Item 57)
  Contents: Daddy, goodbye blues -- Black eye blues -- Deep moanin' blues -- Runaway blues -- Leaving this morning -- Travelling blues -- Sleep talking blues -- Blame it on the blues
- Riverside: RLP 1004, 1950-1959, 1 10-inch sound recording; analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural;; Album title: Muggsy, Tesch and the Chicagoans Performer(s): Muggsy Spanier, cornet; Frank Teschenmacher, clarinet (Box 1, Item 58)
  Contents: China boy -- Bull frog blues -- Friar's Point shuffle -- Darktown strutters' ball -- Nobody's sweetheart -- Whoopee stomp -- Sister Kate -- Jazz me blues
- Riverside: RLP 1011, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Early Harlem piano / James P. Johnson (Box 1, Item 59)
  Contents: Charleston -- I've got my habits on -- Harlem strut -- Vampin' Liza Jane -- Harlem choc'late babies on parade -- Make me a pallet on the floor -- Loveless love -- it takes love to cure the heart's disease
- Riverside: RLP 1017, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Collector's Items: Volume I Performer(s): Richard M. Jones Jazz Wizards; Parham-Pickett Apollo Syncopators; Tiny Parham and his Forty-Five; Clarence Williams and his Orchestra (Box 1, Item 60)
  Contents: Hot and ready -- It's a low down thing -- Mojo strut -- Alexander, where's that band -- A little bit closer - Jim Jackson's Kansas City blues -- Jingles -- Shake 'em up
- Riverside: RLP 1023, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Bix Beiderbecke and the Wolverines Performer(s): Bix Beiderbecke, cornet; Al Gande & George Brunis, trombone; Jimmy Hartwell, clarinet; George Johnson, tenor sax; Dick Voynow, piano; Bob Gillette, banjo; Min Leibrook, tuba; Vic Moore, drums (Box 1, Item 61)
  Contents: Fidgety feet -- Jazz me blues -- Oh baby -- Copenhagen -- Riverboat shuffle -- Sensation -- Lazy daddy
- Riverside: RLP 1025, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Ragtime piano roll: volume 2 Performer(s): Scott Joplin and other, unknown pianists (Box 1, Item 62)
  Contents: Maple leaf rag -- Evergreen rag -- Grizzly bear rag -- The cascades -- States rag medley #8 -- St. Louis tickle -- Jungle time -- 'possum and 'taters
- Riverside: RLP 1029, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Armstrong, Louis, 1901-1971 Album title: Louis Armstrong with King Oliver's Creole Jazz band Performer(s): Joe (King) Oliver, Louis Armstrong, cornets; Honore Dutray, trombone; Johnny Dodds, clarinet; Lil Hardin Armstrong, piano; Bill Johnson, banjo; Warren (Baby) Dodds, drums (Box 1, Item 63)
  Contents: Chimes blues -- Froggie Moore -- Just gone -- Canal Street blues -- Dipper mouth blues -- Weatherbird rag -- Mandy Lee blues -- Snake rag
- Riverside: RLP 1032, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: The great blues singers Performer(s): Bessie Smith; Ida Cox; Ma Rainey; Chippie Hill (Box 1, Item 64)
  Contents: St. Louis blues -- Jail house blues -- I'm so glad -- Soon this morning -- Don't fish in my sea -- Troubled in mind blues -- Careless love
- Riverside: RLP 1033, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Williams, Clarence, 1893-1965 Album title: Clarence Williams: with King Oliver and/or Ed Allen Performer(s): Clarence Williams; Joe (King) Oliver; Ed Allen; Charlie Irvis; Ben Waters; Ed Whittet; Omer Simeon; Buddy Christian; Cyrus St. Clair; Anna Bell; (Box 1, Item 65)
  Contents: Bozo -- Kitchen woman blues -- Lock step blues -- Bimbo -- Beau Koo Jack -- Sister Kate -- Speakeasy blues -- Long, deep and wide
- Riverside: RLP 1034, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Pioneers of Boogie Woogie volume 2 Performer(s): Cow Cow Davenport; Jabo Williams; Charlie Spand; Charles Avery; Henry Brown (Box 1, Item 66)
  Contents: Dearborn St. breakdown -- Polack blues -- Fat mama blues -- Chimes blues -- Eastern Chimes blues -- Deep Morgan blues -- Mississippi blues -- Atlanta rag
- Riverside: RLP 1038, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Morton, Jelly Roll, -1941 Album title: Classic jazz piano: Vol. 1 / Jelly Roll Morton (Box 1, Item 67)
  Contents: Grandpa's spells -- Shreveport stomp -- Kansas city stomps -- Stratford hunch -- Bucktown blues -- Big foot ham -- Perfect rag -- Tom cat blues
- Riverside: RLP 2505, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: New Orleans jazz party / Dixieland Rhythm Kings Performer(s): Dixieland Rhythm Kings (Bob Hodes, trumpet; Charlie Sonnanstine, trombone; Joe Darensbourg, clarinet; Robin Wetterau, piano; Gene Mayl, tuba; Jack Vastine, banjo) (Box 1, Item 68)
  Contents: Blue mama's suicide wail -- Bill Bailey, won't you please come home -- Darktown strutters ball -- Irish black bottom -- Ory's creole trombone -- Melancholy -- St. James infirmary -- Come back, sweet papa
- Riverside: RLP 2512, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: George Lewis Performer(s): George Lewis and his New Orleans All Stars and Quartet (Box 1, Item 69)
  Contents: Darktown strutters ball -- Hindustan -- St. James infirmary -- Some of these days -- Dallas blues -- Red wing -- Lou-easy-an-I-a -- Careless love
- Riverside: RLP 2513, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Lu Watters: 1947 Performer(s): Lu Watters & Bob Scobey, trumpets; Turk Murphy, trombone; Bob Helm, clarinet; Wally Rose, piano; Harry Mordecai, banjo; Dick Lammi, tuba; Bill Dart, drums (Box 1, Item 70)
  Contents: Cake Walking babies from home -- Antigua blues -- Beale street blues -- Chattanooga stomp -- Jazzin' babies blues -- Snake rag
- Riverside: RLP 2517, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Six valves: Don Elliot & Rusty Dedrick Performer(s): Don Elliott & Lyle (Rusty) Dedrick, trumpets; Dick Hyman, piano; Mundell Lowe, guitar; Eddie Safranski, bass; Don Lamond, drums (Box 1, Item 71)
  Contents: Vampire till ready -- When your lover has gone -- Gargantuan chant -- Your own iron -- Easy to remember -- Dominick seventh
- Royal Roost: RLP 410, 1953?, 1 10-inch sound recording; analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural;; Johnny Smith Quintet Album title: Jazz at NBC / Johnny Smith Quintet Performer(s): For jazz quintet featuring Johnny Smith, guitar; other performers Stan Getz, sax; Eddie Safranski, bass; Don Lamond, drums; Sanford Gold, piano (Box 1, Item 72)
  Contents: Moonlight in Vermont -- Tabu -- A ghost of a chance -- Where or when -- Tenderly -- Jaguar -- My funny valentine -- Vilia
- Royal Roost: RLP 417, 1950-1959, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, monaural; Getz, Stan, 1927-1991 Album title: Chamber Music by the Stan Getz Quintet / Stan Getz Quintet Performer(s): Stan Getz; others: Jimmy Rainey; Horace Silver; Len Gaskin; Roy Haynes; Tommy Potter (Box 1, Item 73)
  Contents: Yvette / Gryce -- Potters luck / Silver -- Autumn leaves -- Lullaby of Birdland / Shearing -- Wildwood / Gryce -- Melody express / Gryce -- These foolish things -- Penny / Silver
- Stinson Records: SLP 20, 1950-1959, 1 10-inch sound recording; analog, 33 1/3 rpm; Album title: Jazz variations (Box 1, Item 74)
  Contents: Twelfth Street rag (Fletcher Henderson's Connie's Inn Orchestra) -- Jess stay blues (Jess Stacy) -- Snowy morning blues (James P. Johnson) -- Milenberg joys (Fletcher Henderson's Connie's Inn Orchestra) -- I never knew (Peck's Bad Boys) -- Noni (Jess Stacy)
- Stinson: SLP 21, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: New York Jazz / James P. Johnson Performer(s): James P. Johnson, piano, with assisting jazz artists (Box 1, Item 75)
  Contents: Hot Harlem -- The dream -- Euphonic sounds -- Four o'clock groove -- Hesitation blues -- The boogie dream
- Stinson Records: LP-23, 1950-1959, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, monaural; Granz, Norman, 1918-2001 Album title: Jazz at the philharmonic / Norman Granz Performer(s): Willie Smith; Illinois Jacquet; Charles Ventura; Joe Guy; Howard McGhee; Garland Finney; Ulysses Livingston; Red Callander (Box 1, Item 76)
  Contents: How high the moon / Lewis - Hamilton -- Lady be good / Gershwin
- Stinson: SLP 24, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Album title: Mary Lou Williams jazz concert Performer(s): Mary Lou Williams, piano; Claude Green, clarinet; Don Byas, tenor sax; Jack Parker, drums; Al Lucas, bass; Vic Dickenson, trombone; Dick Vance, trumpet (Box 1, Item 77)
  Contents: Lady be good -- Man o' mine -- Carcinoma -- Jgon mili jam session -- Star dust
- Stinson: SLP 30, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Ragtimers / Muggsy Spanier & Pee Wee Russell Performer(s): Muggsy Spanier, cornet; Vic Dickenson, trombone; Pee Wee Russell, clarinet and vocal; Cliff Jackson, piano; Francis Palmer & Bob Casey, bass; Joe Grausso, drums (Box 1, Item 78)
  Contents: Muskogee blues -- Since my best gal turned me down -- Rosie -- Red hot mama -- Take me back to the land of jazz -- I'd climb the highest mountain
- Stinson: SLP 46, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Sidney Bechet (Box 1, Item 79)
  Contents: Mayette meringue -- Ba ba rhumba -- Magic island meringue -- Tropical mood rhumba -- Sous les palmiers -- Rosa rhumba
- Stinson: SLP 56, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Blind Garry Davis with Sonny Terry and his mouth harp (Box 1, Item 80)
  Contents: I can't make the journey by myself -- Oh what a beautiful city -- Jesus met the woman at the well -- You got to move -- Bad company brought me here -- Motherless children -- Say no to the devil -- Death is riding every day
- Stinson: SLP 58, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Piano rags, stomps and blues / played by Johnny Wittwer (Box 1, Item 81)
  Contents: Sister Kate -- Willie the weeper -- Yonder comes the blues -- Canned meat rag -- Yellow dog blues -- Joe Turner blues -- Ory's creole trombone -- Black and white rag
- Stinson Records: SLP 59, 1950-1959, 1 10-inch sound recording; analog, 33 1/3 rpm;; Album title: Yank Lawson and Bob Haggart Performer(s): Yank Lawson, trumpet; Bob Haggart, bass, whistling; with Jerry Jerome, tenor sax, and his orchestra (Box 1, Item 82)
  Contents: Coniff riff -- Misty blues -- Opus -- Girl of my dreams -- Arsenic and old face -- Ain't misbehavin -- St. Louis blues -- When I grow too old to dream
- Vanguard: VRS-8019, 1955, 1 10-inch sound recording; analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural;; Braff, Ruby, 1927-2003 Album title: Two part inventions in jazz: vol.1 / Ruby Braff and Ellis Larkins Performer(s): Ruby Braff, Trumpet; Ellis Larkin, piano (Box 1, Item 83)
  Contents: Love for sale -- I've got a pocket full of dreams -- blues for Ruby -- I've got he world on a string -- Please -- Old folks
- Vanguard: VRS-8020, 1955, 1 10-inch sound recording; analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural;; Braff, Ruby, 1927-2003 Album title: Two part inventions in jazz, vol.2 / Ruby Braff and Ellis Larkins (Box 1, Item 84)
  Contents: Blues for Ellis -- A city called heaven -- What is there to say -- Sailboat in the moonlight -- When a woman loves a man -- You are too beautiful -- Skylark
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
Jazz; Blues (Music); Ragtime music; Boogie woogie (Music)
Genres
Sound recordings
Associated Material
Additional Guides
All recordings in the collection are cataloged in WorldCat and are available in University at Buffalo Libraries' Catalog, by performing a search under "James B Coover collection of jazz recordings".